[Music]
Hey Fox, continuing the streak of personal accident plans,
today I
bring to you Niva Bappa's
personal accident plan. Friends, Niva Bappa has
always been famous for its
revolutionary and unique plan features.
Like a few days ago, they launched Rish 2.0.
Apart from that, Niva Bappa also has
many unique plan features like
Heartbeat, Family First Health Premia, Go
Active Health Companion.
Continuing its revolutionary streak, Niva Bappa also launched a personal accident plan two years ago
and
this plan also has many unique features.
So let's get to know about Niva Bappa's personal
accident plan. As always, before
starting the video on my digital board,
I would like to give you my disclaimer
that this video is
not sponsored by Niva Bappa Health Insurance Company. This is
my own personal video. And one more
very important thing is that if you have
not yet subscribed to the channel, then
subscribe to it now and
also press the bell icon so that you can get my  Keep
getting notifications of all the videos and also
share this video with your friends and relatives because the information
is very important and useful for everyone and
watch this video from beginning to end, do not skip it.
So let us know about the personal accident plan of Niva Bupa
Health Insurance Company.
Apart from accidental death,
permanent disability and partial
disability are covered in Niva Bupa Personal Accident Policy and also
total temporary disability is covered. Total temporary
disability is a compensation for your income loss
in case of accidental injury,
you will get compensation per week and in Niva Bupa Personal
Accident Policy, this limit is
2 percent of the basic sum assured and its
maximum limit is ₹1 lakh, that is,
if you have taken a one-time policy of ₹50 lakh, then
along with the time limit of ₹1 lakh, you are going to get TTD
compensation, maximum up to ₹1 lakh per week.
100 weeks. Even if you have
left a time limit of ₹1 crore, you will still get ₹1
lakh per week because the maximum
limit is ₹1 lakh per week and
this will be available only for a maximum of 100 weeks. However, if you
are a non-earning member in this policy, then the
limit for the non-earning member will be ₹1 per
of the basic sum assured and the
maximum limit will be ₹5,000 per week, which will be available
only for 50 weeks.
You have time leave options available in this policy
from ₹5 lakh to ₹10 crore and
your eligibility will be 20 times
your annual income. It also
covers the percentage of permanent total disability
and partial disability as a
percentage.
Transportation of mortal remains is covered in this policy.
Transportation of mortal
remains means that if a
person dies accidentally in another city.
So the travel expenses of bringing him from there
to his residence or funeral ground will be
covered, which will have a limit of
1 per of the basic sum and maximum ₹1
lakh. Funeral expenses have also been covered,
its limit is also 1 per of the
basic sum and maximum ₹1 lakh has been covered.
Road ambulance is also covered,
in case of accidental injury, the
expenses of road ambulance for taking the patient from the accident spot to the hospital will be covered,
whose maximum limit will be 000. If for some
reason the road ambulance is not available, then
air ambulance is also covered, which will be
covered up to a maximum % of the basic sum or maximum 5 lakh. Now
let's see what the next slide
says. A rider called loan protector has been added in this plan.
Loan protector means that
if any person other than these  If you have any kind of loan
running like home loan or personal loan, then
it is also covered.
In case of accidental death, permanent disability, major burn, the maximum up to the time limit will be 10%
and only the principal amount of the
loan will be covered. Whatever will be the balance
principal amount, it will be
covered for compensatory hospitalization, the
limit of which has been kept at 10%
of the time limit and maximum 5
lakh hospital daily cash will also be given in it on
25% daily basis, this maximum is
₹5000000.
Monthly Neet Benefit, which is a very
important and unique feature, has been added in this plan.
Monthly Neet Benefit has been added.
In case of accidental death, permanent disability, coma, toss or major burn, monthly Neet Benefit can also be availed,
whose maximum limit will be 10% of the
basic time limit and 000 per month, which will be
given for a maximum of three months. Let's
talk about this plan.  Regarding the next
feature, adventure sports are
also covered in it. Adventure sports like
sky sports, water sports, mountain sports, earth sports,
all these
sports are covered in it, that is,
if the insured dies, becomes
permanently disabled, or
partially disabled while doing any such sports activity, then he will be
covered up to the sum assured. Also, if
you opt for adventure sports,
opt for this feature, opt for this option right
optional rider, then the compatriot
compassionate visit will also be covered.
If a
person gets injured
or dies due to adventure sports, then the immediate family
member can claim the travel expenses to reach him,
whose maximum limit will be
2 per cent of the basic sum assured and a maximum
claim of Rs 50,000 can be taken. Let's see the
next slide, then elderly care
benefit has been added in it. Elderly care
benefit includes accidental death, permanent
disability, major burn and coma.  If the age is
above 60 years, then this benefit will be
given, whose limit will be 10 percent of the
basic time shot and 5 lakhs, but a single
payment will be given, whether there are one or two parents. Let us also
see other benefits. Education
of dependent child will be given 10 percent of the basic time
shot, whose maximum limit is 5 lakhs
in case of accidental death, permanent disability, comatose stage.
Child support will be given through educational counselling
services which are provided through third party.
If the dependent child of the individual is
between 13 years to 23 years, then
this facility will be given to a maximum of two children and
placement services can also be availed
for children between 19 years to 25 years
who are not currently studying.
All these things will be given only in case of accidental death,
permanent disability, coma. The
next slide says that marriage
expenses are also covered
in this policy.  That is, if the insured dies, becomes
permanently disabled,
or goes into a comatose state, then
if his children are of marriageable age, that is, they are
eligible for marriage and are
above 18 years of age, then this facility will be provided.
This is a rider whose limit has been kept at
20 percent of the basic sum assured and a maximum of
10 lakhs. Even if two children are of marriageable age, a
maximum payment of only 10 lakhs will be given.
Broken bone fracture: This is also a
rider added in this.
In case of broken bone fracture, a lump sum amount will be paid, the
maximum limit of which will be ₹1 lakh.
Apart from this, modification of home vehicle, that is, if
any vehicle is completely damaged in an accident
or any house has to be
modified due to this insured
condition, then an amount for that too has been
kept in it. 25 percent of the basic sum assured and a
maximum of 5 lakhs will be given for modification of home and
modification of vehicle.
All these benefits are included in this policy.  There are mostly
optional benefits which you can opt for if you want
or if you don't want you can opt out.
Also, in this policy i.e.
in this personal accident policy,
prosthetics are also covered such as
wheelchairs, couches, hospital beds,
all these things are covered in it or
artificial limbs i.e. artificial
hands, artificial legs, artificial eyes are
also covered which has a maximum limit of
₹1
lakh. In case of comatose condition, a lump
sum amount will be paid 25% of the
basic sum assured and maximum ₹10 lakh. In case of comatose
condition, it means that if a person has
gone into a comatose state due to an accident
and continues to remain in comatose state for 96 years, only then
this benefit will be given
and in case of burns also, a
specific time limit will be given whose
maximum limit will be ₹1 lakh.
In case of burns, a percentage of it is given as to
how much  How much amount will be paid on percentage burn?
In this policy,
a special additional sum assured has been kept for head and spinal injury,
whose limit is % of the basic sum
assured and ₹1 lakh, that is, if there is a head injury
due to an accident or a spinal injury
due to an accident, then this amount will be
paid to the insured. Friends,
another unique feature has been added in this plan
and that is accident care. Accident
care will be provided through outsourcing, that is, through a service
provider.
Accident care means that if the
condition of the insured is such that
we will have to set up an ICU at home, for example,
in case of a serious injury or a major burn, the ICU will be set up at home
through a service provider. Along with this, nursing care will also be provided at home.
Along with that insurance,
blood transfusion will be provided which will be a home
facility, physiotherapy and a single
nurse.  Procedural visit will also be given at home in this.
Also, if due to that accident the
financial condition of that insured has
deteriorated or has been disturbed, then
a financial counseling will also be done
which will be a single session. These entire
services will be given through outsourcing. This is a
unique feature given in this. Let us see
what our next slide says. It is
given in our next slide that there are
five variants in this plan - Variant 1, 2,
3, 4, 5. These variants have been divided feature
wise. The features in variant one are
slightly more than that in variant two. There are
even more than that
in variant four. There are even more than that and
all the features have been added in five. So the
sum options available in this are 5 lakh,
10 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh, 1 crore, 5 crore and
10 crore options are given in this plan
and the annual income i.e.
financial eligibility will be 20
times the annual income of ₹ lakh. If we  If we
talk about variant one then the premium
will be
1316 and for the same 5 lakhs in variant five the
premium will be
444702 friends this is a table in which it is
given according to the variant which
feature is available in which variant as if
if we look at variant one then
accidental death permanent disability and
partial disability will be available in all the variants
and in variant one
accidental hospitalization and road
ambulance will be inbuilt as well if we
talk about TTT then TTT will be
optional in all the five variants that is
you can opt for it or
not and along with that adventurous spots and
lawn protector are
optional benefits for all the five variants as well let's see
variant two in variant two additional
benefit education of dependent
children has been added and
child support has also been added whereas
in variant three apart from these,
hospital daily cash broken bone
benefit funeral expenses air ambulance
com toss  Benefit after benefit,
prosthetics, and wheelchair have also been
added to this policy in variant three.
Similarly, in variant five, we have added
transportation of motor vehicles,
whereas transportation of motor vehicles has been included
in variant two but
not in variant three.
If we talk about variant five, all the features have been added in variant five,
and these two and
three features will always be optional.
Premium-wise, if we look at the
policy, it is not very expensive and is
economical at ₹1 crore. If we
look at the premium, the premium in variant one is ₹1 lakh,
and in variant five, the
premium is ₹11,000.
1 crore is a standard amount. Generally, if we
purchase a policy of ₹1 crore, then the
premium in variant one will be ₹
13,567 on ₹1 crore. Similarly, the premium in variant five will be
₹2,000,000, which are neither available in any life insurance
policy nor in any term
insurance policy.
I have explained it to you in this video,
so thank you so much friends
for staying till the end of this video. If
you have
any doubts or queries related to Niva Bopa Personal Accident Policy, then
you can ask me in my comment box and you
can also ask me by mailing me. Friends,
Personal Accident Policy is as important for us as it is important to
reach the airport on time when we go on a travel. Thank you so much friends
and have a day.